

Niket Shukla

Mississauga, Ontario | 1-647-863-5646 | niketshukla108@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Front-End Developer, with 5 years of experience developing SPA's using JavaScript and React JS. Experience of working on multiple projects in an agile environment with strict timelines to create customized, visually pleasant, and user-friendly designs. Strives to emphasize scalable and well-documented codes that can be maintained for reusability. Effectively materialized client preferences into straightforward and visionary products using HTML, CSS, React JS, and JavaScript. Implemented Redux state management library. Utilized CSS preprocessors such as SASS and LESS to create clean and well-organized code. Understanding of package managers, such as NPM, and Yarn. Managing, tracking, and documenting code changes using the GIT version control system.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- SASS
- JavaScript
- React JS

- Responsive Web Design
- WordPress
- Heroku
- MongoDB

WORK HISTORY

REACT DEVELOPER

06/2022 to Present

Pro-Tek Consulting | Los Angeles, California

- Designed multiple dynamic and browser-compatible websites using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript
- Working on an admin dashboard for logistic client using React JS and TypeScript to adding type definitions to the functions and variables
- Made use of ES6 features and functional components to optimize driver and vehicle components
- Implemented Redux and Redux Thunk to manage app's state in a single place and keep changes more predictable and traceable
- Managed to implement rich data-driven web applications by consuming RESTful APIs
- Followed Test-Driven Development to minimize future bug fixes by running automated tests using Jest library

REACT DEVELOPER

02/2022 to 05/2022

Tech Mahindra | Mississauga, Ontario

- Worked in a team of 3 and followed the end-to-end process to integrate UX design for Futuri Tether Widget
- Coded a redesigned radio widget using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript increasing its usability and performance
- Utilized React JS by building different components of the widget which improved the reusability of the code
- Worked in an agile-driven environment to effectively complete projects within stipulated timeframe by utilizing available resources



Niket Shukla

Mississauga, Ontario | 1-647-863-5646 | niketshukla108@gmail.com

FRONT END DEVELOPER

05/2020 to 01/2022

Next Decipher | Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Served multiple clients by communicating empathetically to understand their technical requirements, design flow, data security, and operational needs
- Produced multiple visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code, producing high-quality markup using HTML5 and CSS3
- Worked on TCI dashboard for wholesaler's using React JS by leveraging functional components
- Implemented React Hooks to maintain state in functional components as well as implement life cycle methods
- Made use of Recharts library to show data fetched by consuming Rest APIs using Axios
- Worked with CSS preprocessors SASS for better scalability and reusability of code

FRONT END DEVELOPER

05/2015 to 10/2019

Creative Mantra | Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Collected, defined, and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans
- Built cross-browser compatible and accessibility-compliant websites, resulting in faster load time using HTML5, CSS3, and Flexbox or Bootstrap
- Developed reusable components using React JS for an application thus improving the response time
- Implemented automated tests to ensure high-quality and reliable codes according to the industry's best practices
- Utilized Fetch and Promises to make API calls and retrieve data in the form of JSON
- Maintained workflow and tracked changes using GIT version control

JR. FRONT END DEVELOPER

11/2013 to 04/2015

Creative Mantra | Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers
- Analyzed requirements to design, develop, or improve software applications for multiple websites
- Continuously improved websites by redesigning and coding to enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings
- Oversaw troubleshooting of technical and responsive issues to solve problems quickly and efficiently

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Applications | Engineering Technology Sardar Patel Institute of Technology, Mumbai

05/2013